Guide to the Speech Communication Department Records 1918-1996
Oregon State University Libraries, Special Collections & Archives Research Center
- Paper Records, 1918-1996; Subgroup 2
  - National Defense Education Act (NDEA) Institute in English: Advanced Communication Skills, 1965-1968; Series V
    - Reports, 1965-1967
      - Plan of Operation, 1967 (Box 1)
      - Proposal for NDEA Summer Institute in Advanced Communication Skills, 1965-1967 (Box 1)
      - Final Report, 1967 (Box 1)
    - Schedules, 1967 (Box 1)
  - Committees, Organizations, and Conferences, 1933-1989; Series VI
    Series VI consists of the records of department committees, student organizations, and conferences and includes materials pertaining to forensics at Oregon State during the 1930s-1950s.
    - Curriculum Committee, undated (Box 1)
    - Dramatics Committee, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Executive Committee, 1969-1970 (Box 1)
    - Oregon High School Drama Conference, 1959-1963 (Box 1)
    - Oregon Speech Association, 1960 (Box 1)
    - Forensics, 1933-1954
      - Associated Students, Forensic Division - accounting ledger, 1934-1949 (Box 1)
      - Intercollegiate Forensic Tournament of Champions, 1950-1952 (Box 1)
      - Pacific Forensic League events, 1933-1954 (Box 1)
    - Philosophies Committee, undated (Box 1)
    - Seminars Committee - School of Humanities and Social Sciences, 1961 (Box 1)
    - Speech Chair Search Committee, 1988-1989 (Box 1)
    - Television Committee, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Publications, 1940-1996; Series VII
    Series VII includes the program for the Model United Nations of the Far West 40th annual session; clippings; and a newsletter to theater departments at Oregon community colleges regarding a theater festival.
    - Model United Nations 40th Annual Session conference book, 1990 (Box 1)
    - Newspaper Clippings, 1940-1996 (Box 1)
    - Oregon Community College Festival newsletter, 1977 (Box 1)
  - Reports, 1949-1974; Series VIII
    Series VIII consists of reports, primarily from the 1950s and early 1960s, documenting the academic programs and activities of the Speech Department.
    - Accreditation - Northwest Association of Secondary and Higher Schools, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Annual Reports, 1957-1962 (Box 2)
    - Biennial Reports, 1956-1962 (Box 2)
    - The Philosophy and Future of Drama at Oregon State College, circa 1961 (Box 2)
    - Policies and Procedures, 1960s-1974 (Box 2)
    - Report on Extempore, Impromptu, Experimental, and Discussion at Oregon State College, 1949-1950 (Box 2)
    - Report on the Model United Nations of OSU, 1964 (Box 2)
    - Speech Screening Test, 1954-1960 (Box 2)
    - Text Evaluation, circa 1962 (Box 2)
    - Student Speech Activities at Oregon State College, undated (Box 2)
    - A Statement on Operational Principles for the Department of Speech, undated (Box 2)
    - Future Quarters for Department of Speech at Oregon State College, undated (Box 2)
  - Scrapbook, 1964-1970; Series IX; 2 folders (Box 2)
    Series IX consists of a scrapbook assembled by the Speech Communication Department documenting Oregon State University theater productions, KBVR-TV programs, workshops, department faculty news, campus free-speech regulations, and a performance by a visiting San Francisco Mime Troupe. The scrapbook is predominantly newspaper clippings; it also includes brochures and flyers. The scrapbook was originally housed in a three-ring binder.
  - Subject Files, 1948-1961; Series X
    Series X consists of materials documenting speech courses and activities pertaining to live television. The series also includes biographical information for Paul Knoll, a Speech Department faculty member from 1927 until his death in 1957.
    - Biographical file on Paul X. Knoll, 1948-1957 (Box 2)
    - Speech 111 course materials, undated (Box 2)
    - Television - live, 1961 (Box 2)